Guide to the New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council Records WAG.123
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council Records
circa 1930-1987
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council
Ward, Peter
WAG.123
96 Linear Feet in 96 record cartons
The New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council was born in of Depression-era struggles to improve conditions for employees of New York City hotels, restaurants and private clubs. Several unsuccessful strikes and the emergence of a powerful Hotel Association representing the employers, spurred this effort. In April of 1938 the Council was formed as an umbrella group of five AFL-affiliated unions and given sole authority to bargain for those unions. Over the years many other independent unions and locals have affiliated with the Council. In addition to industry-wide bargaining, the Council took on the work of administering welfare funds and running training and community service programs for its affiliates as a group. The collection consists of administrative files of the Council, correspondence and other files of Council presidents Jay Rubin and Vito Pitta, an extensive series of files arranged by the names of individual hotels, photograps, and records of the welfare funds and social service programs amdinistered by the Council.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Given on deposit by the New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council via two donations, in 1996 and 2007, under an agreement with Peter Ward, President of the Council. The accession number associated with this collection is 1997.026.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of administrative files of the Council, correspondence and other files of Council presidents Jay Rubin and Vito Pitta, an extensive series of files arranged by the names of individual hotels, and records of the welfare funds and social service programs amdinistered by the Council.
Arrangement
Minutes are arranged by type of meeting, and; other series are arranged alphabetically.
The files are organized into seven series:
Missing Title
Minutes, 1938-1986
Presidents' Files, 1943-1990
General Files, 1930s-1989
Hotel Files, 1930s-1986
Neighborhood Service Councils, 1961-1976
Unprocessed Material, 1950s-1990.
Archived Website
Historical/Biographical Note
The New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council was born in of Depression-era struggles to improve conditions for employees of New York City hotels, restaurants and private clubs. Several unsuccessful strikes and the emergence of a powerful Hotel Association representing the employers, spurred this effort. In April of 1938 the Council was formed as an umbrella group of five AFL-affiliated unions and given sole authority to bargain for those unions. Over the years many other independent unions and locals have affiliated with the Council. The Council took on the work of administering welfare funds and running training and community service programs for its affiliates as a group.
In the early 1930s conditions for workers in New York hotel and restaurant industry were harsh. Hours were long, work was seasonal, benefits were non-existent and there was no minimum wage. To make matters worse, gangsterism, which had flourished in the years of Prohibition, was rife in the industry. The The American Federation of Labor-affiliated Hotel and Restaurant Employees Union concentrated its efforts on restaurant workers to the detriment of unskilled and semi-skilled workers in hotels. The failure of a 1934 strike sparked by a walkout of kitchen and dining room workers at the Waldorf Astoria led to several mergers of small independent unions attempting to gain leverage in confrontations with the powerful Hotel Association, representing hotel owners. In 1937 a newly formed Hotel, Restaurant and Cafeteria Employees Organizing Committee, led by left-wing militants, Jay Rubin, Miguel Garriga and Michael Obermeier, ran a hugely successful organizing campaign that further raised expectations.
In February 1938 eleven locals merged to form Hotel and Restaurant Employees Local 6. Local 6 was given juridiction over all hotel employees except those who were already members of building trades unions. On April 26, 1938 five unions joined together to form the Hotel Trades Council: H.E.R.E., Local 6; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 3; Building Service Employees International Union, Local 32A; International Brotherhood of Operating Engineers, Locals 94 and 94A; and International Brotherhood of Firemen, Oilers and Maintenance Mechanics, Local 56. The Council's first victory, in March 1938, was an agreement by the Hotel Association all grievances of union members would be taken up with the HTC. In subsequent years many other unions or locals either merged into Local 6 or joined the Council individually. In terms of numbers, Local 6 was the largest group in the Council and the most active in its affairs.
Jay Rubin was elected as first president of the Council, a position which he held until his retirement in 1978. Born in Gradno, Poland in 1904, Rubin had worked as and upholsterer and a baker before becoming a union organizer. He served on the Executive Board of the New York Central Labor Council and the Executive Bopard of the New York Copnvention and Visitors Bureau. A champion of improved health care for workers, he was an officer of the Hospitl Review and Planning Council of Southern New York, the New York State Advisory Board of Medicaid, and the Labor-Management Council of Health and Welfare Plans. Rubin died in New York City on August 12, 1990.
In January 1939 the Council concluded a comprehensive wages and hours agreement, with strong support from New Deal state and municipal authorities. Among its historic provisions were time-and-a-half pay for overtime, paid vacations, free uniforms, a curb on split shifts, dues checkoff, an anti-discrimination clause, no dismissal for union activity, and establishment of an arbitration procedure. While some hotels signed the agreement immediately, many others held out for years -- the last few signing in the 1950s.
In 1944 the HTC achieved an industry-wide, employer-financed and union-managed benefits program. A Hotel Joint Employment Agency was established under the 1949 contract -- a major remedy against seasonal fluctuations and discriminatory or arbitrary hiring practices; after a period of adjustment this no-fee agency was fully functioning by 1951, when 22,000 jobs were supplied to members. A Health Center, offering free basic medical care to hotel workers and their families, was opened in 1950. In 1966 the Hotel Trades Council established the Neighborhood Service Councils, which provided members with a wide range of services, from housing assistance to legal advice and medical referrals. It has also run a Hotel Industry Training Program, including a school for for young people seeking work in the industry and for workers interested in upgraing or changing their category of employment.
Over the years the Council expanded to include unionized painters, telephone operators, maintenance workers, upholsterers, clerical workers and others employed in hotels, restaurants and clubs. By the 1980s, when the Council was headed by Rubin's successor, Vito J. Pitta, the HTC represented 25,000 members affiliated with nine locals of eight international unions. While continuing to struggle against economic downturns, and anti-union or dishonest employers, especially in smaller enterprises throughout the City, the Council claims to offer, through its contracts, the best wages and benefits available to hotel workers anywhere in the world.
Separated Material
Photographs were separated and established as the New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council Photographs (PHOTOS 097). Films were separated and established as the New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council Films (FILMS 011).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Custodial History
The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Membership lists.; New York (N.Y.); Waiters.; Agreements.; Hotels |x Employees |z New York (State) |z New York.; Clubs |z New York (State) |z New York.; Clippings (information artifacts); Photographs.; Hotels |z New York (State) |z New York.; Bartenders.; Minutes (administrative records); Correspondence.; Rubin, Jay; Pitta, Vito J.; Hotel Association; Hotel Employees & Restaurant Employees International Union; New York Hotel Trades Council; New York Hotel and Motel Trades Council; Ward, Peter
- Series I: Minutes, 1938-1986
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I: Minutes, 1938-1986, consists largely of minutes of meetings the Hotel Trades Council's Executive Board and of the Staff Grievance Board.
  - Executive Board, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Executive Board, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Executive Board, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Executive Board, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Executive Board, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Executive Board, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Executive Board, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Executive Board, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Executive Board, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Executive Board, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Executive Board, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Executive Board, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Executive Board, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Executive Board, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Executive Board, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Executive Board, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Executive Board, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Executive Board, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Executive Board, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Executive Board, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Executive Board, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Executive Board, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Executive Board, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Executive Board, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Executive Board, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Executive Board, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Executive Board, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Executive Board, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Executive Board, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Executive Board, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Executive Board, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Executive Board, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Executive Board, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Executive Board, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Executive Board, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Executive Board, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Executive Board, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Executive Board, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Executive Board, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Jan 1967-Jun 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Jul 1967-Dec 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Jan 1968-Jun 1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Jul 1968-Dec 1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Jan 1969-Jun 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Jul 1969-Dec 1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Jan 1972-Jun 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Jul 1972-Dec 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Mar 1973- Jul 1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Jan 1974-Jun 1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, Jul 1974-Dec 1974 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Staff / Grievance Board, May 1979; Aug 1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Insurance, Pension and Medical Fund, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Series II: Presidents' Files, 1943-1990
  Series II: Presidents' Files, 1943-1990, is divided into two sub-series. Sub-series A: Jay Rubin Files, includes biographical material on Rubin, administrative files of the HTC, and files reflecting his interests in health care issues and in hotel-worker organizing efforts in Puerto Rico. Sub-series B: Vito Pitta Files, contains files of Rubin's successor as president. The sub-series consists mainly of Pitta's "Daily Files" (or work logs) for 1982-1986, and also includes "Daily Files" of several other HTC staff members.
  - Subseries II:A: Jay Rubin Files, 1943-1990.
    - Biographical, undated; 1957-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Book Project (Mehling), 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - CATHA, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1953-1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Dues Book, 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Dues List (By Hotels), undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Election Tally, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Employment Agreement (Rubin), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Equal Pay for Maids and Housemen, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - George Farm, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 10a)
    - Healthcare (Speech), 1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Health Center Survey, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Health Program Manual, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Hospitals, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Hotels: General, 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Kennealy, John, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Miami Strike, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Negotiations, 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Negotiations, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - New Politics: Article on Local 6, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Payroll/Compensation, 1957-1969 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Pension; Welfare Funds, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Puerto Rico, undated; 1963-1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Study program, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Summary Reports, Jun-Dec 1957 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Summary Reports, Jan 1958 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Summary Reports, Feb - Mar 1958 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Summary Reports, Apr-Jun 1958 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Summary Reports, Jul-Dec 1958 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Summary Reports, Jan-May 1961 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Summary Reports, Jun-Dec 1961 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Tips, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Union Family Medical Fund: Statistics, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Union History, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Subseries II:B: Vito Pitta Files, 1981-1986.
    - Kelly, Adam: Daily File, Aug - Dec 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Kelly, Adam: Daily File, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Lynch, Louis: Daily File, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Lynch, Louis: Daily File, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lynch, Louis: Daily File, Apr-Jul 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Lynch, Louis: Daily File, Aug-Dec 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - McSweeney, Janet: Daily File, Oct-Nov 1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - McSweeney, Janet: Daily File, Dec 1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Office File: General, Jan-Jun 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Pitta, Vito: Biographical File, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Jul-Sep 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Dec 1984-Apr 1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, May 1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Jun-Sep 1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Oct-Dec 1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Jan-Apr 1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, May-Aug 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Sep-Dec 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Jan-Feb 1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Mar 1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Apr 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, May 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Jun 1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Jul 1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Aug 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File (Re: Millard Cass) 1 of 2, Aug 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File (Re: Millard Cass) 2 of 2, Aug 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Sep 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Oct 1-15 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Oct 15-Nov 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, Dec 1986 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Pitta, Vito: Daily File, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Pitta Defense Fund Committee: Letter Sent, [1983] (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Smith, Walter: General File, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Smith, Walter: General File, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Strike Materials, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Series III: General Files, circa 1930-1989
  Series III: General Files, 1930s-1989, contains extensive files documenting the HTC's relations with the Hotel Association, bargaining materials, agreements, grievance files, arbitration decisions, pension fund materials, and files on the HTC-sponsored Industry Training Program. Also included are files on the individual local unions affiliated to the HTC, and topical files on a wdie range of issues germane to the hotel and restaurant industries.
  - Accretion Clause, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Adam, Claus: Sheet Music, 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Agreements, 1948-1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Agreement: Samples, undated; 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Agreements: Hotel Association, 1953-1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - AIDS, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ANG Organizer, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Assessment Referendum, Undated; 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Associated Hospital Service of NY, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Atlantic City, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Bargaining, 1959-1971 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Bargaining, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Bargaining, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Bargaining: Clippings, 1938-1946 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Bargaining Dept., 1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Bargaining: Strike Vote, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Bing and Bing Management (Landlord), 1965-1979 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Bing and Bing Management (Landlord), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Bing and Bing Management (Landlord), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Book Check, Undated; 1983 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Broadway Theater Statistics, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Business Agents: Lists, 1970-1985 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Business Meals Deduction, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - By-Laws, 1942-1986 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Canada: Hotels... Union, Local 261, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Cariola, Samuel F., undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Carnegie Deli, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Child Identification Tags, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Child Labor, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Christmas Greetings, Undated; 1959 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Cleaning Contractors, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Columbia Teachers College, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Columbus Day, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Columbus Day Dinner (V. Pitta), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Committees, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Comparative Wage Scales, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Computer Issues, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Conferences, 1947-1964 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Convention Center, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Convention Report: Problems of New York, c.1960 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Cornish Arms: Collective Bargaining Agreement, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1945; 1959-1972 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Defense Fund (HTC), 1947-1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Defense Fund (HTC), 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Defense Fund (HTC), 1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Delegates, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Delegates Manual, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Dental Fund, 1977-1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Dinner Dance (Rubin Tribute), 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Discrimination in Hotel Employment, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Discrimination in Hotel Employment: Training Program, 1963-1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Dues (HTC), 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Dues Ledger, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Elections, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Election Materials: Contending Locals, 1930s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Equal Pay Case (HTC v. Hotel Association), 1963-1977 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Enlarged Council, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Executive Board: General, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Ferrara, Fred, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Finances, 1978;1982 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Finance Committee, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Forty Sixth Street Theaters, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Friendly Furniture Inc. and HTC Agreement, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Functions, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Funds: Pension, Medical, etc., 1979-1983 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - General Industry Minimum Wage Board, 1962-1966 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Golden, Frank, Undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Grievances: General, 1951-1953 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Grievances: General, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Grievance Board, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Health and Safety, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Health Care (HTC), 1949-1961 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Hilton Hotels: NLRB Case, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hotel Association, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hotel Association: Agreements, 1943-1945 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hotel Association: Agreements, 1952-1969 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Hotel Association: Annual Dinner, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Hotel Association: Bargaining, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Hotel Association: Contract issues, 1981-1987 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Hotel Association: Correspondence, Jan-May 1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Hotel Association: Correspondence, Jun 1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Hotel Association: Correspondence, Jul 1986 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Hotel Association: Correspondence, Aug 1986 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Hotel Association: Correspondence, Sep-Dec 1986 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Hotel Association: Equal Pay Claims, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Hotel Association: Hearings, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Hotel Association: This Month, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Hotel Association: Union Family Medical Plan, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - HERE v. Bakery and Confectionery International Union, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - HERE: Roster of Locals, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Hotel Lists, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Hotel Employees Sports League, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - HTC Realty Corp., 1954-1963 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - HTC Realty Corp., 1964-1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Health Center, 1950-1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Hotel Tax, 1952-1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Hotel Tax, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hotel Wages, 1960-1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hotel (Weekly Publication), 1946-1957 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Housing, 1955-1963 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - IBEW, Local 3, 1953; 1973-1977 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - IBEW, Local 3, 1978-1986 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Impartial Chairman, 1963-1976 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Impartial Chairman, 1978-1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Impartial Chairman, May-Jun 1986 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Impartial Chairman: Awards, Jan- Apr1977 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Impartial Chairman: Awards, May-Sep 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Impartial Chairman: Awards, Oct 1977-Dec 1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)